Guide to the Political magazine collection, Puck, Judge, Jingo, 1881-1885, 1925 MS2238
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Political magazine collection, Puck, Judge, Jingo
1881-1897, 1925
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cohen, Edward
Kessler, Robert L.
Chapman, Elizabeth
MS2238
1.25 Linear Feet
This collection contains issues of the political magazines Puck, Judge, and Jingo. The issues date from 1881-1885, and 1925.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Edward Cohen in 2007 and 2008. Judge issue October 24, 9125 was a gift of Robert L. Kessler 2017 November 28 (accession 2017.072). Vol. 32 No. 804 "The Inauguration" was a gift of Elizabeth Chapman 2019 April 23 (Accession 2019.022), Robin Masefield donated digital copies of the front covers of Judge vol. 16 nos 403 and 410 (accession 2020.024).
Historical Note
Puck magazine, weekly magazine, founded by cartoonist Joseph Keppler, began publication in March 1871. Keppler had been working for Frank Leslie's Illustrated The original Puck publication had both English and German editions. Puck started as a German-language weekly but an English version appeared the following year in March, 1877. The 16 page magazine sold for ten cents. For several years the English language magazine operated at a loss and was subsidized by the German version. However, circulation gradually increased and by the early 1880s Keppler was selling over 80,000 copies a week.
Typical 32-page issues contained a full color political cartoon on the front cover and a color non-political cartoon or comic-strip on the back cover dealing with social issues. There was always a double-page color centerfold, usually on a political topic. There were numerous black & white cartoons used to illustrate humorous anecdotes. A page of editorials commented on the issues of the day, and the last few pages were ads. Some of Joseph Keppler's main targets were the women's suffrage, trade unions, and religious hypocrisy. Keppler died in 1894 and his son, Joseph Keppler, Jr. assumed control. Harry Leon Wilson became editor until being replaced in 1904 by John K. Bangs, the former editor of Harper's Weekly. The English magazine continued for over forty years under several owners and editors until it was bought by the William Randolph Hearst company in 1916 (or 1917). The publication continued for two more years and the last edition was distributed in September 1918.
Jingo and Judge are similar to Puck in layout and content.
[this history was adapted from an article in wikipedia and the website http://www.spartacus.schoolnet.co.uk/ARTpuck.htm]
Collection Scope and Content
The collection has issues of Puck, Jingo, and Judge magazine from 1881-1885 and one issue from 1925.
Collection Organization
Arranged chronologically by publication.
Cartoons and comics; Judge (New York, N.Y.); Political cartoons; Puck (English edition); Cohen, Edward; Kessler, Robert L.; Chapman, Elizabeth
- Puck magazine vol. IX No. 212, 03/30/1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 354, 12/19/1883 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 355, 12/26/1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 356, 01/02/1884 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 358, 01/16/1884 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 360, 01/30/1884 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 361, 02/06/1884 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 362, 02/13/1884 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 363, 02/20/1884 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Puck magazine vol. XIV No. 364, 02/27/1884 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 365, 03/05/1884 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 366, 03/12/1884 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 368, 03/26/1884 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 369, 04/02/1884 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 370, 04/09/1884 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 371, 04/16/1884 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 372, 04/23/1884 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 373, 04/30/1884 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 374, 05/07/1884 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 375, 05/14/1884 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 376, 05/21/1884 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 377, 05/28/1884 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 378, 06/04/1884 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 379, 06/11/1884 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 380, 06/18/1884 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 381, 06/25/1884 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 382, 07/02/1884 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 383, 07/09/1884 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 384, 07/16/1884 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 387, 08/06/1884 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 388, 08/12/1884 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 389, 08/20/1884 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Puck magazine vol. XV No. 390, 08/27/1884 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 392, 09/10/1884 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 394, 09/24/1884 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 395, 10/01/1884 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 397, 10/15/1884 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 398, 10/22/1884 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 399, 10/29/1884 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Puck magazine vol. XVI No. 400, 11/05/1884 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Puck magazine vol. XVIII No. 444, 09/09/1885 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Puck Magazine centerfold cartoon titled A few snap-shots at the "powers that be" in the average commercial house., 1897 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Jingo vol. 1 no. 1, 09/10/1884 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jingo vol. 1 no. 6, 10/15/1884 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Jingo vol. 1 no. 7, 10/22/1884 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Jingo vol. 1 no. 8, 10/29/1884 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Jingo vol. 1 no. 9, 11/05/1884 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Jingo vol. 1 no. 10, 11/12/1884 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Jokes from the Judge, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- The Judge vol. 6 no. 143, Vol 32 No. 89 and Vol. 89 no. 2295, 1884 July 12, 1897, 1925 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Judge (portions of issues), 1882 July 15 -29 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Marla Williams 2020 December 17 (2020.033)
  Scope and Contents
  For the Judge issue dated July 15, 1882 this folder contains the front cover and for the issue dated July 29 1882 the folder contains a cartoon.
- Judge Magazine issues vol. 16 no. 403 and no. 410, 1889 July 06 - 24 August 1889; MS2238; 2 digital object(s)
  Gift of Robin Masefield 2020 May 25 (2020.023)
  The images are only the front covers of each issue.